{
    "id": "11bfd39d878d4cd0911e3b8274366786",
    "title": "Tenses Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "This is the 6th time, you ………………………. the same question.",
            "description": "The present perfect is used after this is the first /second/last etc. ",
            "answers": [
                "asked",
                "are asking",
                "have asked"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "9adc0a153f5e4cdb9dfcaa7b4ea20ad1"
        },
        {
            "question": "I ………………………. a strange experience yesterday.",
            "description": "Use the simple past to say that something happened sometime ago. ",
            "answers": [
                "have",
                "had",
                "am"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "62361148a37c4df7972542dcc23f6890"
        },
        {
            "question": "As soon as she saw me, she …………………….. towards me.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "rushed",
                "had rushed",
                "have rushed"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "e342477f2b124a99a937a945abd991f4"
        },
        {
            "question": "Those who are against this proposal …………………………. their hand.",
            "description": "Rise is intransitive raise is transitive. ",
            "answers": [
                "should rise",
                "should raise",
                "would raise"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "45bc3406a0e64218945febb4ee7dc839"
        },
        {
            "question": "She asked if I ………………………… her cat.",
            "description": "Present perfect in the direct speech becomes past perfect in the indirect speech. ",
            "answers": [
                "saw",
                "have seen",
                "had seen"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "9ab5f292c499456b90bcb33404883e76"
        },
        {
            "question": "Although I had all the qualifications, my application …………………………….",
            "description": "Use the passive form here because the subject is not the doer. ",
            "answers": [
                "rejected",
                "was rejected",
                "had rejected"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "96564a3030aa4cff86bc709d84f67352"
        },
        {
            "question": "Despite her best efforts, she …………………………… pass the test.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "does not",
                "could not",
                "has not"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "cb0d80e6341f444494c1deb03d989303"
        },
        {
            "question": "He said he regretted that he ………………………. so hastily.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "acts",
                "acted",
                "had acted"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "3c2b40f7c7664d81b6a9a1b752a167d6"
        },
        {
            "question": "He …………………………… for incompetence.",
            "description": "A passive verb is required here because the subject is not the doer of the action. ",
            "answers": [
                "dismissed",
                "was dismissed",
                "was dismissing"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "422dadc4fce14e1782f5c87fcc4323b1"
        },
        {
            "question": "He was clever but he …………………………. industry.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "lacks",
                "lacked",
                "was lacking"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "a6b2eea5a3054d72be0599001fbab843"
        },
        {
            "question": "As they were poor, they …………………………. great hardship.",
            "description": "When one verb is in the past tense, the other verbs too will most probably be in the past tense. ",
            "answers": [
                "suffered",
                "suffers",
                "suffer"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "e99b8ac7d0974a098acebf699b6988a7"
        },
        {
            "question": "I conceded to his request because I ………………………….. to disappoint him.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "do not want",
                "did not want",
                "does not"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "a28c0ad14bf844d7b9aa60dccb8b25f9"
        }
    ]
}